How we doing?
>> What was the process like for you? You
went from winning a Super Bowl to
becoming a free agent and then finding
out your new home is going to be with
the Bengals.
>> Uh it was very interesting. It was kind
of fast, you know, you know, winning the
Super Bowl, doing those festivities, and
then, you know, after that having a
little bit of time to really figure out
things, and then coming to Cincinnati,
I'm excited. you know, it was one of
those situations that kind of you're
still processing still a [laughter]
little bit.
>> What makes you excited to come here?
>> Uh the opportunity, you know, I feel
like coming here, talking to the
coaches, you know, talking about what
their plans for the future and what they
want to do and build here. And that's
what excites me is, you know, being
somebody to be in part of that building
and part of seeing it grow. That's
that's what excites me is like
Cincinnati has what they need. And it's
one of those teams that people are going
to know about soon. What do you think
you bring to the defense?
>> Uh, you know, coming from a winning
program, coming from, you know, I think
for me it's one of those things I just
want to bring energy. I want to bring
that light, you know, I want to bring
something that, you know, a little bit
of that effort, uh, chasing and just
being one of those people that you can,
how do I describe I'm trying to find the
words to describe it, but one somebody
that can be a light for the defense to
be like, "All right, look, I'm going to
go do what I got to do." You know what
I'm saying? Make sure we can bring
everybody up. There's a lot of young
guys with a lot of talent on the team
and I feel like, you know, bringing that
with Brian, me and everyone we're
bringing into the team, I feel like that
could be very helpful to the team that
we could create something and build
something there.
>> How would you describe your your four
years in Seattle?
>> My four years in Seattle, uh, you know,
it was very interesting have two
different coaches, you know, two
different staffs and learned a lot.
Learned a lot of football and I feel
like every year I've played the game,
I've just learned that much more about
the game. And going from my first two
years to last year to the Super Bowl, I
just saw a lot about the game and saw a
lot of different aspects. So I feel like
my knowledge has grown every year and I
just use that on the field.
>> The Bengals clearly see potential in
you. Untapped potential.
>> What do you think that is? What's the
next level for you?
>> Uh, you know, to put it all together,
you know, a lot of things a lot of
people question about me is like the
production. And that's a big question. I
understand that. But the thing is is the
coaches saw the film, they saw what I
can do on the field, and they want to
tap in and make sure that the pressure
weight and all that turns into sacks,
you know, and so with them, with me
buying in and getting that chance to
really dig into that and really get into
the nitty-gritty of what I need to do to
improve my game, I feel like that can
the unt uh untapped potential can really
show itself.
>> Knowing what it takes to have a
championship defense, you certainly know
that now. How much does that help you
even though you're not the entire team,
but being one guy who's seen it now
coming to this team?
>> I mean, it helps a lot. You know,
obviously for me, I know what it looks
like and seeing what it's, you know,
being on one and seeing what it looks
like. You know, obviously you can attest
to those things and tell, you know, it's
one thing to be like, I think that's
what it looks like, but it's another
thing to be actually be able to say
you've seen it. To be able to say you've
done it and then be able to say like, I
actually know what it actually looks
like. How did your role kind of change
in Seattle between both coaching staffs
and what did you kind of learn about
what you can do by doing a little some
different things maybe in McDonald's
scheme versus the prior?
>> Uh, for sure. I feel like the biggest
thing I understand is the ability to be
versatile, you know, putting me in
different positions, playing rushing
from a three, rushing from a nine,
playing six, you know, all the different
ways they were using me in Seattle,
dropping coverage, you know, especially
with Mike, a great coach. He knows a lot
about defense, knows a lot about
football. So it taught me a lot, you
know, showed me how to look at things,
how to make the game simplified for
myself and uh using that to my advantage
now and understanding that okay, I know
this different facet of the game. I know
this different avenue and being able to
use that.
>> How long does the euphoria of a Super
Bowl title last? Are you still feeling
it or does it wear off pretty quick?
>> Uh I mean it's one of those it's in the
moment like in the moment it's there.
the week after it's there. But, you
know, obviously now I'm in a new city,
new team, and now I'm just trying to get
back to it.
>> I mean, that's the one thing you guys
all chase and then you get it. Is it is
it hard to walk away from that?
>> Uh, for sure. I mean, it's definitely,
but that's, you know, it's time for a
new chapter, time for, you know, to do
it again and try to get back to it.
>> You mentioned production.
>> Mhm.
>> 2023, you had [clears throat] nine
sacks.
>> If after that season, I would have said
you're going to have eight sacks over
the next two years. What do you think
you would have said? I have said
probably not. I said I would have
thought more, but go ahead.
>> Do well. Do you think how you were used
in 2023, is that part of their vision
here for you? Even though you you've
grown as a player, do you think that
that's the the fit?
>> Uh, I believe so. I believe that's what
they brought me in here to do to be, you
know, bring that back into the light,
you know, be that pass rusher, be that
person to, you know, help in the pass
rush, helping the defense on all downs.
And that's what I want to do when I come
here, you know, make sure that bring
that, you know, bring that championship
mentality and that bring that level to
the game.
>> In researching the researching you the
last couple of days,
>> it it seems like your dad is someone
that you spoke about being a a really
big part of your life and inspirational
to you. Why?
>> Uh, you know, my dad taught me how it
would work. You know, one thing I can
attest to is I used to wake up for high
school at 6:00 a.m., 7 a.m. to go to
school, but he was somebody that I'd
wake up and he had already been in his
office for an hour. And seeing him do
that day in and day out. But also a
testament to it is the fact that he
never ever ever asked for
accomplishments, never asked for a pat
on the back. He just did it in the dark.
And I feel like that's kind of an
adapted me to show that, you know, my
mindset with things is when you work,
you work for to get better, to do what
you need to do, not for the
accomplishment, not for the claps, not
for the, you know, acknowledgement. You
know, you do your job because that's
what you're supposed to do.
>> Do you know anyone from this team or has
anyone from this team reached out to you
yet?
>> Yeah, some guys have reached out. You
know, me and the guys, I met some guys
today, you know, so it's it's exciting.
It's like it's all fresh. It's all new
and I'm just excited to be here. excited
to be in the city, you know, get to get
a little familiar with it. Still
figuring out didn't realize how close we
were to Kentucky, but you know,
[laughter]
it's a little bit it's a little bit new,
but I'm excited.
>> Is there [clears throat] anything that
you did know about Cincinnati before you
came here or anything that kind of
surprised you other than Kentucky?
[laughter]
>> Uh, no. Figuring out, honestly, it's
it's all really new to me. I've been
here uh one time before we played here
and now really making it my home. So,
I'm excited to do that.
>> Feels like in a lot of ways this locker
room is looking for leaders, for veteran
leaders uh on defense at least. I know
you talked about that a little bit, but
how much of that is part of who you are
and what you hope to be here?
>> I was blessed to be in a room with a lot
of great uh leaders, a lot of veteran
guys, guys been in the league 10 plus
years, 12 plus years. So, being with
them for two, three years now,
understanding what it looks like and
understanding how to lead and how to do
that part really helped me in my game.
It really knows what it looks like. and
knows how to lead a room and show how
the room is supposed to be led. And so
those type of things are things that I
saw for the last couple years of my
career and now it's my time to apply
those.
>> Are there any pass rushers you watch on
tape? Guys from around the league,
anybody you try to emulate or anybody
who has your style that you try to use?
>> Uh, I watch everybody. I feel like pass
rush is such a versatile thing. To me,
pass rush is art art form. And when it
comes to pass rush, you got to really be
versatile. You got to know that not
every situation is just cookie cutter.
And every guy pass rushes in their own
way, their own form, but you can take a
little bit from everybody. And I think
that's the thing is if you don't adapt,
you don't see that there are different
ways to pass rush, then you'll, you
know, you'll stay stagnant. And being
able to learn from everybody and be able
to take little facets really has been
helpful to me. I mean, from my rookie
year to now, I feel like I've learned so
much about it and learned so many
different ways. And especially when I
meet guys and talk to guys around the
league, I ask everyone for a nugget. And
it doesn't matter who you are. To me, I
can learn from anybody.
>> Who's the best nugget? What was the best
nugget and who didn't come from?
>> Uh, my best nugget.
My best nugget actually came from a
coach of mine in college and he told me,
uh, pass rush, you were the one
dictating the terms. And when you take
control of it instead of trying to
react, it helps you a lot. You
referenced the the pressure rate
earlier. If you're self scouting
yourself, what's what's the biggest key
to converting that pressure rate to the
sacks?
>> Uh the facet of, you know, this game is
fast. You know, there's a lot there's
very people don't realize how minute and
how small the details are into it. I can
you can be one step away from 10 sacks
or you could be, you know, one step too
short. And so just understanding how to
make that process faster, shortening up
my, you know, my steps, how quick I can
get to the quarterback, how much faster
I can get there, and no matter how small
the details are, but those details will
make a difference.
>> Do you feel like you're ready to be a
leader on a young defense? And and what
do you think your leadership style is?
>> For sure. Uh, you know, that's what they
brought me in here to do, be a leader.
So that's what I my job is to do. And
obviously for me, my leadership style is
to be a lead by example. You know, I'm
the type of person that's going to go
out there and show you what it looks
like and tell you to follow along.
>> Have you talked to Brian at all?
>> Yeah, we we came in together and
[clears throat] I'm excited to be here
with him. I think he's going to be a
great leader on this team. I think he's
going to be help with this defense a lot
and it's exciting to see, you know, to
have the conversation. We were talking
on the flight end and really talking to
each other about what we see the vision
and I think I'm excited for it.
>> How valuable could the three rings that
you guys walked?
>> I think does that matter? I feel like it
does help you because I feel like that's
like I said earlier uh you know a lot of
people have that question of like what
does it look like you know what is it is
this really what it takes and for him
and me we both know yeah this is what it
takes you know what I'm saying it's one
of those questions of quote unquote
doubt what people would like to say but
there is no doubt when you know what it
looks like
>> you said you were on the same flight
private or was it commercial
>> I was just on the same flight [laughter]
I know your former Minnesota Gopher
teammate Tanner Morgan is only from like
20 miles from here over in
>> Oh, yeah.
>> in Kentucky. So, you mentioned Kentucky.
So, you may have somebody to talk to
about getting to know Kentucky better
now.
>> For sure. Definitely. You know, I'll
definitely be reaching out figuring out
the city. I didn't once I realized that
I was like, "Oh, I know exactly who to
call." So, I'll definitely call Tanner,
have a conversation, show me around a
little bit.
>> Thanks.
>> Perfect. Thank you. Appreciate it. Thank
you.